Finding Aid for Center for Afroamerican and African Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1966-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Black student activism 1969-2001
  - Other activism 1966-2000
    - United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) 1987-1990
      - Newsletters and Fliers 1988-1990 (Box 4)
      - Principles of Unity circa 1989 (Box 4)
      - Publicity and Events 1987-1990 (Box 4)
      - Publicity and Events,1988 (Box 4)
      - Steering Committee 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - United Coalition against Racism (UCAR) / Baker-Mandela Center (BMC) 1986-1993
      - Activism, Gulf War Protests 1991 (Box 4)
      - Administrative Records 1986-1993 (Box 4)
      - Administrative Records 1987-1993 (Box 4)
      - Board Meetings 1988-1992, 7 folders (Box 4)
      - Brochures 1989-1990 (Box 4)
      - Budget, Actual and Projected 1988-1992 (Box 4)
      - Budget, Fundraising and Tax Exemption 1988-1991 (Box 4)
      - Budget, Grants, and Activities 1989-1990 (Box 4)
      - Budget and Events 1989-1990 (Box 4)
      - By-Laws 1989 (Box 4)
      - Campus Police Deputization 1990-1992 (Box 4)
      - Contributions Received 1988-1989 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence 1987-1992
        - BMC Listserv 1993 (Box 4)
        - Fundraising 1987-1989 (Box 4)
        - General 1987-1989 (Box 4)
        - National and Regional Conferences 1988-1990 (Box 4)
        - Requests for Information 1987-1989 (Box 4)
        - Membership 1992 (Box 4)
      - Disk Backups, Administrative and Budget Records 1989-1991 (Box 5)
      - Disk Backups, Library and Outreach Records 1989-1991 (Box 5)
      - Diversity Training, Facilitator Feedback 1992 (Box 5)
      - Donations 1988 (Box 5)
      - Founding and History 1988-1989 (Box 5)
      - Fundraising Letter 1990 (Box 5)
      - Membership 1989 (Box 5)
      - Michigan Alliance of African-American Students and Michigan State University Protests 1989 (Box 5)
      - Michigan Survival Summit, Minutes and Resolutions 1992 (Box 5)
      - People of Color Conference (Box 5)
      - Phone Logs 1992 (Box 5)
      - Programs and Events 1985-1993, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Programs and Events, Proposed Speakers 1988-1990 (Box 5)
      - South Africa, 1990(?) (Box 5)
      - Unity Tenants' Organization 1990 (Box 5)
    - University of Michigan 1970-1989
      - Mandatory Course on Racism Proposal 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Minority Enrollment 1970-1982 (Box 5)
      - Newspaper Clippings, Race on Campus 1987-1988 (Box 5)
      - Programs and Events 1992 (Box 5)
      - Programs and Events 2000 (Box 5)
      - South Africa and Divestment, Michigan Pension Funds 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Washtenaw County Coalition Against Apartheid (WCCAA) 1976-1987
      - Corporate Letters to U-M Regarding Investment in South Africa 1978, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Foreign Investment in South Africa 1977-1980 (Box 5)
      - Harare Youth Conference on South Africa 1986-1987 (Box 5)
      - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility 1976-1979 (Box 5)
      - Kalamazoo Conference on South Africa and Divestment (4/12/1980) 1980 (Box 5)
      - Michigan House Bills for Divestment,1978-1980 (Box 5)
      - Midwest Conference on University and Corporate Involvement in South Africa 1978 (Box 5)
      - Minutes and Administrative Records 1978-1979 (Box 5)
      - Newspaper Clippings, Namibia 1978-1979 (Box 5)
      - Newspaper Clippings, Race Issues and Divestment at U-M 1978-1979 (Box 5)
      - Northeast Coalition for the Liberation of Southern Africa 1978-1979 (Box 5)
      - South Africa and Divestment 1979-1980 (Box 5)
      - U-M Regents and Open Meetings Act 1979 (Box 5)
- Blacks at U-M 1969-2007
  Th,e Blacks at U-M, 1969-2007 series (4.5 linear ft.) concerns civil rights and anti-apartheid activism on the University of Michigan campus and in the surrounding community from the 1970s to the 1990s. This series includes records of political and student organizations that were active on campus, with the exception of UCAR and the BMC, mentioned above. This collection also includes a small number of topical files and records pertaining to offices and policies of the University. This series is comprised of six subseries: Organizations, 1984-1995 (1 linear foot.), Programs and events, 1981-2004 (0.5 linear ft.), Publications, 1975-1999 (0.5 linear ft.), Student organizations, 1972-2007 (1 linear ft.), Topics, 1971-1995 (0.2 linear ft.) and University of Michigan, 1969-1997 (1.4 linear ft.).
  - Organizations 1984-1995
    - Academic Women's Caucus 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Association of Black Professionals and Administrators 1984-1995
      - Awards 1988-1989 (Box 6)
      - Bylaws 1986-1990 (Box 6)
      - Email (printouts) 1991-1993, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - General 1984, 1990-1995, 7 folders (Box 6)
      - Membership 1993 (Box 6)
      - Minutes 1987-1990, 1992-1993, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Networking Committee, Pamela Kay Bruner 1989-1990 (Box 6)
      - Newsletters 1988-1994 (Box 6)
      - Reports and Surveys 1985-1989, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Center for Research on Social Organization 1993 (Box 6)
    - Graduate Student Teaching Assistant Training Program 1991 (Box 6)
    - Men of Color 1990 (Box 6)
    - National Council for Black Studies 1993 (Box 6)
    - Network for Equal Economic Development Service, Inc. 1992 (Box 6)
    - Pro-Choice Action 1992 (Box 6)
    - Programs and Events, Joint 1987-1993 (Box 6)
    - Puerto Rican Solidarity Organization 1992 (Box 6)
    - Women of Color Task Force
      - Career Conference 1987, 1989-1990, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Conferences and Awards 1983-1991 (Box 6)
      - General 1990-1992 (Box 6)
      - Minutes 1986-1995, 4 folders (Box 6)
      - Programs and events 1986-1990 (Box 6)
  - Programs and events 1981-2004
    - Black History Month 1986-1995 (Box 7)
    - King/Chavez/Parks Visiting Scholars Program 1987-1991 (Box 7)
    - Kwanzaa 1987, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr., Commemorations 1981-1999, 2001-2004, 11 folders (Box 7)
    - Mike Wallace Commencement Speech 1987 (Box 7)
    - Publicity 1985-1995 (Box 7)
  - Publications 1975-1999
    - The African, 1975 (Box 7)
    - Ann Arbor News, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
    - Black Perspectives, 1980, 1987-1989 (Box 7)
    - Black Student Monthly, 1995-1999, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Consider, 1986-1993 (Box 7)
    - HUES Hear Us Emerging Sisters, 1993-1999, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - I Have a Vision of, Wade McKee Scholars, 1990 (Box 7)
    - International Observer, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - LSA Magazine, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Miafric, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Daily, 1987-1992 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Review, 1990-1993 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Today and Agenda, 1988-1992 (Box 7)
    - Minority Counseling and Information Newsletter, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Research News, 1982-1991, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Shaking Through, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Sothis, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Street News, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Student organizations 1972-2007
    - African-American Students in Design 1990 (Box 8)
    - African Students Association 1991 (Box 8)
    - Association of Black Journalists 1990-1992 (Box 8)
    - Black Business Student Association 1990-1993 (Box 8)
    - Black Law Student Alliance 1985-1993 (Box 8)
    - Black Pre-Medical Association 1988-1993 (Box 8)
    - Black Student Athletes 1986-1993, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Black Student Media Coalition 1986 (Box 8)
    - Black Student Medical Association 1988-1992 (Box 8)
    - Black Student Psychological Association 1972, 1988-1992 (Box 8)
    - Black Student Union 1969, 1987-2007
      - General 1987-2000, 8 folders (Box 8)
        (Includes printouts from email distribution list)
      - History 1969 (Box 8)
      - Publications 1990, 2002, 2005-2007, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Black Students 1986-1993, 3 folders (Box 8)
      (Includes printouts from the "BSN" list within the MTS system)
    - Black Theater Group 1985-1993 (Box 8)
    - Black Undergraduate Law Association 1991-1993 (Box 8)
    - Caribbean Students' Association 1989, 1992, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Directories 1985-1992 (Box 8)
    - Force for Black Women 1991-1993 (Box 8)
    - Global African Dialogue Series 1990-1991 (Box 8)
    - Greeks 1984-2007
      - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority 1987-1996, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity 1984-1999 (Box 8)
      - Angel Club 1990-1991 (Box 8)
      - Black Greek Association 1986-1990 (Box 8)
      - Delta Sigma Theta Sorority 1991-1993 (Box 8)
      - Diamond Auxiliary/Dymonz 1990-1994 (Box 8)
      - Kappa Alpha Psi Fraternity 1989-1992 (Box 8)
      - Omega Psi Phi Fraternity 1991-1992 (Box 8)
      - Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity 1990, 2007 (Box 8)
      - Sigma Gamma Rho Fraternity 1992 (Box 8)
      - Zeta Phi Beta Sorority 1988-2001 (Box 8)
    - Haiti Solidarity Group 1993 (Box 8)
    - Kuumba Players 1990-1992 (Box 8)
    - Lesbians of Color Collective (LOCC) 1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Student Assembly (MSA) 1986-1993 (Box 8)
    - Minority Organization of Rackham 1989-1990 (Box 8)
    - Multiracial/Multicultural Group 1991-1993 (Box 8)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People 1985-1991 (Box 8)
    - National Black Graduate Student Association 1990-1991 (Box 8)
    - Programs and Events, Joint 1989-1993 (Box 8)
    - Public Health Students of African Descent 1991-1993 (Box 8)
    - Sistahs Organizing in Unity for Real Change (SOURCE),1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - Society of Minority Engineers (SMES),1990-1993 (Box 8)
    - Students of Color of Rackham (SCOR) 1992-1995 (Box 8)
  - Topics 1971-1995
    - Affirmative Action 1985-1997 (Box 9)
    - Community Announcements 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - Concerns 1991-1993 (Box 9)
    - Courses 1990-1993 (Box 9)
    - Faculty and Staff Positions 1973-1975, 1986-1990 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Recruitment and Hiring 1973, 1983-1988 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Retention 1986-1991 (Box 9)
    - Financial Aid 1991-1993 (Box 9)
    - Intergroup Relations 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - Multicultural Courses 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - Political Correctness 1991 (Box 9)
    - Racism, Institutional 1971, 1987-1992 (Box 9)
    - Religion 1986-1988 (Box 9)
    - Student Recruitment, Admissions, Enrollment, and Retention 1987-1993 (Box 9)
    - Student Recruitment and Enrollment 1973-1986 (Box 9)
    - Student Retention 1986-1988 (Box 9)
    - Women 1988-1995 (Box 9)
  - University of Michigan 1969-1997
    - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Air Force ROTC 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Area Studies 1991 (Box 9)
    - Career Planning and Placement 1990 (Box 9)
    - Coalition for the Use of Learning Skills 1979-1982 (Box 9)
    - Comprehensive Studies Program 1984-1992
      - General 1987-1992 (Box 9)
      - Mentoring Program 1984-1992, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Dearborn Campus 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Flint Campus 1987, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Housing 1973-1997 (Box 9)
      - General 1990-1993 (Box 9)
      - Minority Councils 1985, 1988, 1990-1993 (Box 9)
      - Minority Lounges 1973-1993 (Box 9)
      - Minority Peer Advisors 1990-1991 (Box 9)
      - Publications 1979-1994 (Box 9)
        (Including Ethnic Reflections)
      - William Monroe Trotter House 1981-1997 (Box 9)
    - Minority Student Orientation 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    - Minority Student Services 1976-1995
      - Black Student Leadership Dialogue 1985-1992 (Box 9)
      - General 1984-1995, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Publications 1976-1990 (Box 9)
    - Office of Affirmative Action 1974-1987 (Box 9)
    - Office of Financial Aid 1987, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Office of Minority Affairs 1988-1993
      - General 1988-1993, 3 folders (Box 9)
        (1-3 of 5 folders)
      - General 1988-1993, 2 folders (Box 10)
        (4-5 of 5 folders)
      - Historically Black Colleges and Universities Committee 1992 (Box 10)
      - Staff Listing 1993 (Box 10)
    - Office of the President 1988-1992 (Box 10)
    - Opportunity Awards Program 1969-1971 (Box 10)
    - Personnel 1975-1997
      - Administration 1986-1990 (Box 10)
      - Alumni 1983-1999, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Faculty 1975-1997, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Regents 1988-1991 (Box 10)
      - Staff 1984-1993 (Box 10)
    - Policies 1988-1990 (Box 10)
    - Sexual Assault and Prevention Awareness Center 1988-1993 (Box 10)
    - Speakers 1986-1993 (Box 10)
    - Undergraduate Library, Peer Information Counseling 1987-1989 (Box 10)
    - University Library, Diversity Task Force 1988-1995 (Box 10)
    - Vice President of Academic Affairs 1992-1993 (Box 10)
    - Vice President for Research 1986-1991 (Box 10)
    - Vice President for State Relations 1990 (Box 10)
    - Vice President for Student Services 1991-1992 (Box 10)
    - Vice Provost for Minority Affairs 1988-1993 (Box 10)
- Organizational archives of CAAS 1962-2010
  The third series, CAAS organizational archives, 1962-2010 (17 linear ft.) includes correspondence and administrative files; course descriptions and syllabi; articles and research by faculty members and visiting scholars; and fliers and programs from CAAS events. The series is divided into nineteen subseries: Administrative records, 1970-2010 (1 linear ft.), Brown bags and colloquia, 1970-1998 (0.6 linear ft.), Committees and meetings, 1974-1993 (0.2 linear ft.), Conferences, 1991-2002 (1 linear ft.), Co-sponsored programs, 1979-1995 (0.1 linear ft.), Courses and syllabi, 1970-2009 (1.9 linear ft.), Directors files, Kevin Gaines, 1974-2009 (restricted) (0.7 linear ft.), History, 1970-1981 (0.2 linear ft.), Library, 1970-2000 (0.6 linear ft.), Persons, faculty, 1962-2005 (5 linear ft.), Persons, non-faculty, 1986-2001 (0.1 linear ft.), Programs and events, 1972-2002 (0.3 linear ft.), Publications, 1971-2000 (0.6 linear ft.), Research projects, 1982-1997 (1 linear ft.), Rodney, Walter, Student Essay Competition, 1985-1997 (0.1 linear ft.), Study abroad, 1986-2005 (0.4 linear ft.), Working papers, 1990-1998 (1.1 linear ft.), Photographs, 1997-1994 (0.8 linear ft.) and Posters, (1 outsized folder).
  All of these subseries are arranged alphabetically, with the exception of the Working Papers subseries. That subseries derives from faculty and graduate student conferences and lectures in the 1990s and its arrangement derives from a numbering system used by CAAS. Not all of the papers were transferred, as there are gaps in the sequence.
  The records in the largest subseries, Persons, faculty, 1962-2005 (5 linear ft.), are not personnel files and do not contain sensitive information but are primarily biographical, and consist largely of publications by and about faculty members. Occasional administrative records can also be found among the faculty records.
  Researchers interested in the history of CAAS will find useful material in the History subseries in Box 16, and in the audio and video recordings relating to the 20th Anniversary of CAAS in 1991. Reports on the results of the Ford Foundation-funded research projects, referenced above in the administrative history of the unit, are given in the Research projects subseries, under the heading "Ford Foundation Project."
  - Administrative records 1970-2010
    - Administrative Assistant, Correspondence 1971 (Box 11)
    - Assistant Director, Correspondence 1983, 1990-1992 (Box 11)
    - CAAS at 35 Program 2006 (Box 11)
    - CAAS at 40 Program 2010 (Box 11)
    - Collection documentation and catalogs 1988-1991 (Box 11)
    - Constitution and bylaws 1971 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, Faculty 1987-1992 (Box 11)
    - Directors 1970-1992
      - Johnson, Lemuel 1986-1990, 7 folders (Box 11)
      - Lewis, Earl, Correspondence 1990-1992 (Box 11)
      - Lynch, Acklyn, Correspondence 1970 (Box 11)
      - Mazuri, Ali A., Correspondence 1978-1981 (Box 11)
      - Sudarkasa, Niara, Correspondence 1980-1985 (Box 11)
      - Yates, J. Frank, Correspondence 1970-1971 (Box 11)
    - Search committee, Distinguished Lecture Series 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Honorary Degree Nomination for Nelson Mandela 1985-1991, 5 folders (Box 11)
    - Newsletters, African Studies 1999-2009 (Box 11)
    - Newsletters, CAAS 2007-2009 (Box 11)
    - Physical Facilities 1983-1984 (Box 11)
    - Programs and events
      - Campus Lockdown: Women of Color Negotiating the Academic Industrial Complex 2008 (Box 11)
      - Common Wind: Conversations in African American and Atlantic Histories 2008 (Box 11)
      - Not sponsored by CAAS 2000-2010 (Box 11)
      - Sponsored by CAAS 2003-2010 (Box 11)
    - Proposals
      - Curriculum 1972-1988 (Box 11)
      - Funding 1992 (Box 11)
      - Honors Program 1987-1988 (Box 11)
      - Research 1986-1990 (Box 11)
    - Publicity 1989-1993 (Box 11)
    - Public Relations 1980-1992 (Box 11)
    - Retreats 1988-1989 (Box 11)
    - Reviews of CAAS Faculty Work published 2001-2008 (Box 11)
    - Staff meetings 2006 (Box 11)
    - Student retention report 1983 (Box 11)
    - Summer Workshop on Quantitative Methods and African Studies, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Brown bags and colloquia 1970-1998 (mostly publicity) (0.6)
    - Chronological 1970-1998, 19 folders (Box 12)
    - Dialogue Series 1991-1995 (Box 12)
    - Race, Culture, and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry 1991-1992, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Committees and meetings 1974-1993 (0.2 linear ft.)
    - Committee Membership 1985-1992 (Box 12)
    - Curriculum 1974-1991, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Executive 1978-1991 (Box 12)
    - Faculty 1979-1993, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Research 1983-1988 (Box 12)
    - Service 1980-1988 (Box 12)
  - Conferences 1991-2002 (1.0)
    - Archaeology of the African Diaspora 2001 (Box 13)
    - Constitution-Making in South Africa 1997 (Box 13)
    - Gender and Urban Policy 1996, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - General 1970-1989 (Box 13)
    - Graduate 1991-2002 (Box 13)
    - First Annual Graduate Student Multidisciplinary Conference: Challenging Paradigms of the Diaspora 1991, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Second Annual Graduate Student Multidisciplinary Conference: Second Generational Themes in Africana Studies 1992, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Seventh Annual Graduate Student Multidisciplinary Conference: Voices in a Mosaic: Creating Multicultural Communities in the Academy 1997 (Box 13)
    - Eighth Annual Graduate Student Multidisciplinary Conference: Highlighting the Multidisciplinary Scholarships of Students of Color 1998 (Box 13)
    - Seventh Annual Midwest Graduate Student Conference in African Studies 2002, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Robert Hayden, Tribute 1980 (Box 13)
    - Robert Hayden, Words in the Mourning Time 1990, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Twentieth Anniversary Conference: Reflections and Revisions 1970-1990, 1991, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Urban Underclass 1992, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - World the Diaspora Makes 1992, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Co-sponsored programs 1979-1995 (0.1)
    - Chronological files 1979-1995, undated, 11 folders (Box 14)
  - Courses and syllabi 1970-2009 (1.9)
    - Chronological files 1970-1994, 28 folders (Box 14)
      (1-28 of 45 folders)
    - Chronological files 1994-2009, 27 folders (Box 15)
      (29-45 of 45 folders)
    - CAAS 104.001, Images of African-American Women 2005 (Box 15)
    - CAAS 105, Introduction to African Studies 1991 (Box 15)
    - CAAS 333.001, Blacks, Indians, and the Making of America 2003 (Box 15)
    - CAAS 338, African-American Literature on Racial Passing 2001 (Box 15)
    - CAAS 558 Quantitative Analysis and the Study of Africa 1996 (Box 15)
    - Honors Program 1989-1990 (Box 15)
    - Enrollment 1983-1987, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Faculty Evaluations 1983-1987 (Box 15)
    - Pilot 189/Sociology 204, Intergroup Relations and Conflict 1991 (Box 15)
  - Directors files, Kevin Gaines 1974-2009
    - African Initiative-Rackham 1996 (Box 26)
      [ER RESTRICTED until July 1, 2032 ]
    - African Studies Steering Committee 2005 (Box 26)
    - Budget Request FY 2006-7 2004 (Box 26)
    - CAAS External Review and Plan 1995 (Box 26)
    - CAAS Five Year Strategic Plan 1992-2000 (Box 26)
    - CAAS Five Year Strategic Plan 2006-2007 (Box 26)
    - CAAS Five Year Strategic Plan Surveys 2007 (Box 26)
    - Committee Assignments 2001-2009 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence 1995-2009 (Box 26)
    - Curriculum and teaching 1992-2009 (Box 26)
    - Diversity 2007 (Box 26)
    - Executive Committee 2003-2007 (Box 26)
    - Faculty meetings 2000-2009 (Box 26)
    - Ford Foundation Project 1998 (Box 26)
    - Funding proposals 2003-2007 (Box 26)
    - General 1974-1998 (Box 26)
    - Gift agreements 2007 (Box 26)
    - Haniff, Nesha undated (Box 26)
    - Michigan State Collaboration 2005 (Box 26)
    - MOSES 2003 (Box 26)
    - Strategic budget and planning 2008 (Box 26)
    - University of Dar es Salaam 2009 (Box 26)
      (Faustin Maganga and Kelly Askew)
  - History 1970-1981
    - History of the Center and Program 1970-2000, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - History, Master of Arts Program 1970-1976 (Box 16)
    - History, Triennial Report 1978-1981 (Box 16)
  - Library 1970-2000
    - America's Greatest Negroes 1970 (Box 16)
    - Bibliographies 1970-1992, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Class Handouts 1986 (Box 16)
    - Exhibits 1980-1992
      - Black History Month, Correspondence 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - Black History Month, Publicity 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - Black History Month, Wesley, Charles 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - Black Odyssey 1981-1982 (Box 16)
      - Jules Bledsoe 1981-1982 (Box 16)
      - Calendar 1991-1992, 12 folders (Box 16)
      - Immigration and Blacks (Box 16)
      - Malcolm X Undated (Box 16)
      - King, Martin Luther Undated (Box 16)
    - Librarians, Glover, Denise, Correspondence 1981 (Box 16)
    - Librarians, Hall, Jo Anne, Correspondence 1986-1991 (Box 16)
    - Librarians, Hortense, Howard, Correspondence 1976 (Box 16)
    - Manual 1987 (Box 16)
    - Mazrui Collection Bibliographic Project 1990 (Box 16)
    - Projects, Acquisitions Catalog 1989-1992 (Box 16)
    - Proposals Undated (Box 16)
    - Public Relations 1986-1990 (Box 16)
    - Public Relations, Open House 1995 (Box 16)
    - Reports 1978-2000 (Box 16)
    - Statistics 1988, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Persons, faculty 1962-2005
    - Adebiyi, Nike 1989 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Bazel 1980-1985 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Richard 1986-1987 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Walter R. 1976-1989 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Walter R., Publications 1978-1989, 5 folders (Box 17)
    - Askew, Kelly 1999-2005 (Box 17)
    - Atkins, Keletso 1983-1995 (Box 17)
    - Atkins, Keletso, Publications 1986-1995, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Awkward, Michael 1985-1995 (Box 17)
    - Awkward, Michael, Publications 1993-1997 (Box 17)
    - Boubacar, Barry 1995 (Box 17)
    - Bowman, Phillip 1980-1991 (Box 17)
    - Bonilla-Silva, Eduardo undated (Box 17)
    - Brown, Elsa Barkley 1990-1996 (Box 17)
    - Bryant, Bunyan 1981-1990 (Box 17)
    - Chrisman, Robert 1989-1993 (Box 17)
    - Clark, Gracia 1988-1992 (Box 17)
    - Clark, Gracia, Publications 1988-1992 (Box 17)
    - Cogburn, Derrick 1998 (Box 17)
    - Cooper, Frederick 1983-1993 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold 1970-2005 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Bibliography 1992-1993 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Biography and Interviews 1973-1988 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications 1950-1978 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book and Play Reviews 1969-1971 (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book Reviews of "Crisis," 1967-1991, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book Reviews of "Plural But Equal," 1981-1991 (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book Reviews of "Rebellion or Revolution," 1968-1973 (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Essays 1962-1979, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Davis-Roberts, Christopher 1977-1985 (Box 18)
    - Dawson, Michael 1988-1993 (Box 18)
    - Dawson, Michael, Publications 1988-1990, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Demerson, Bamidele 1974-1987 (Box 18)
    - Deskins, Donald 1990-1992 (Box 18)
    - Deskins, Donald, Publications 1969-1984 (Box 18)